# Dipesh R. Patel

E-mail:- dipesh291187@yahoo.com

Mobile: - +91 7567550655

### **OBJECTIVE:-**

Seeking suitable opportunity as **SR. INSTRUMENT TECHNICIAN** in the process control industry with major responsibilities that will effectively utilize my commissioning, maintenance, communication, and organizational skills.

### **Summary:-**

12 Years: - experience in Modern Process Control Instrumentation of Refinery, Petrochemical and Oil/gas industries at various positions in India and abroad. Involved in, Commissioning and Start up as well as Maintenance activities in different location. Gained very good experience in Routine Maintenance, Preventive Maintenance and Corrective as well as Shutdown Maintenance in different facilities. Well Experience in fault finding, troubleshooting and start up of process control instrument, equipment in Process Plant. Aware of permit to work, standard maintenance procedure, Safety procedure required to carry out safe and smooth job in Industries. Worked in different type of activities related to Commissioning, Trouble Shooting, Overhauling Loop checking, Repair, Calibration and Maintenance of varies kinds of electronics, pneumatic and Hydraulic instruments. During job have got very good command on Flow, Pressure, Temperature, Level, compressor Instruments, Analytical and Fire & Gas related field Instrumentation and Bently Nevada Vibration monitoring system and PLC related control system.

#### **Education:-**

Education	CLASS / YEAR	University
I.T.I. in INSTRUMENT MECHANIC	Aug 2004 to July 2006	Industrial Training Institute, Bilimora
DIPLOMA INSTRUMENTATION & CONTROL	Nov 2006 to dec 2009	Institute of Business Management & Engineering

# **Experience in Abroad:-**

Name of Organization	Period	Position
NPCC through AI Mansoor Enterprise (UMM LULU SUPER COMPLEX) (OFFSHORE)	26/06/2017 to 07/01/2020	Senior Commissioning Instrument Tech.
ENKA TEKNIK, IRAQ (AL NAJYBIA POWER PLANT)	31/12/2014 to 30/05/2015	Senior Commissioning Instrument Tech.
ENKA Insaat ye Sanayi A.S. IRAQ (ERBIL COMBINE CYCLE POWER PROJECT)	16/10/2013 to 08/07/2014	Senior Commissioning Instrument Tech.
ERAM ENGINEERING, SAUDI ARABIA	08/12/2012 to 04/04/2013	Instrument Tech.
IBN ZAHR (SABIC GROUP), KSA	05/01/2013 to 31/03/2013	Instrument Tech.

Mari Time Industrial Services Co LTD.INC. [M.I.S.], Sharjah, DUBAI	14-00-2010 to 08-04-2012	Commissioning Instrument Tech.
Enoc Processing Company L.L.C. [E.P.C.L.] Jabel-Ali, DUBAI.	10-11-2011 to 14-12-2011	Instrument Tech.

## **Experience in India:-**

Name of Organization	Period	Position
GUJRAT THEMIS BIOSYN LTD	07/05/2009 to 08/12/2010	Instrument Tech.
BILAG INDUSTRIES PVT.LTD.	05/10/2006 to 30/09/2008	Instrument Tech.

#### **Professional Experience:-**

Employer : NPCC (OFFSHORE) ( ADNOC UMM LULU SUPER COMPLEX)

**Designation**: SR. Commissioning Instrument Technician

**Duration**: 26/06/2017 to 07/01/2020

In 2208 PAKAGE 2 UMM LULU SUPER COMPLEX (ULAP,ULUTP,ULSP,ULGTP) and also working PACKAGE 1 in WHT 3, 5 & 6, in super complex GAS TURBINE PGT 25+ & Water Treatment Plant, Water Injection Pumps, Gas injection system, Air Compressors, Responsibilities involve in commissioning loop check all this system and skids and trouble shooting of instruments, cause & effect, functional test all type of instruments, start-up activitys ....

**Employer**: ENKA TEKNIK (AL NAYBIA POWER PLANT) IRAQ

Designation : SR. Instrument Technician

Duration : 31/12/2014 to 30/05/2015

- I am working in Commissioning Department, Responsibilities involve in simple cycle power station, gas turbine (**GE- FRAME 9E**) & bop areas & water treatment plant, Instrument calibration, loop check and commissioning and trouble shooting of instrument, functional test all type of instruments, start-up activitys ....
- Calibrating of all type of Transmitter like PT., LT., TT., FT., etc...
- Calibrating of Control Valve like Fisher Mesolenieon etc... Also check PSV...

**Employer**: ENKA (ERBIL COMBINE CYCLE POWER PROJECT) IRAQ

Designation : SR. Instrument Technician

Duration : 16/10/2013 to 08/07/2014

- I am working in Commissioning Department Good Experience in Cause & Effect, POTPS, Function test, Calibration, Loop checking, commissioning and startup activities and trouble shooting of instrument.
- I have known all type of Instrument Loop check from process control Instrument.
- Well aware of Layout Drawings, P&ID, Loop Diagrams etc...

**Employer**: **ERAM ENGINEERING, SAUDI AREBIA.** 

**Designation**: Instrument Technician

**Duration**: 08-12-2012 TO 04-04-2013.

I am working in Maintenance Department,

- I have known all type of Instruments Troubleshooot, Loop check from process control Instrument.
- Well aware of Layout Drawings, P&ID, Loop Diagrams.

**Employer**: MARITIME INDUSTRIAL SERVICE CO.LTD. E [M.I.S.], DUBAI.

**Designation**: Instrument Technician

**Duration**: 23-05-2010 TO 07-04-2012

- Configuration, Calibration and troubleshooting of various types of process control instruments.
- Preventive, corrective and diagnostic maintenance of all kinds of Instruments. Troubleshooting, repairing, calibration of various types of process control instruments. Loop checking, precommissioning checks, up-gradation and maintenance services.
- Installation and Calibration of Electrical and Pneumatic type Instruments.

**Employer**: **ENOC PROCESSING COMPANY L.L.C.** [E.P.C.L.], **DUBAI**.

**Designation**: Instrument Technician

**Duration**: 10-11-2011 TO 14-12-2011

- I am working in Commissioning Department as a contract period for 1 Month.
- I Handled Pre-Commissioning and Commissioning Activates, and Calibrating of different type of Transmitter, also Check Thermocouple and RTD etc...
- I Have done Smart Transmitter like Rosemount, Fisher, Model No.-3051, 1151, 644 etc.

**Employer**: GUJRAT THEMIS BIOSYN LTD AT VAP.

**Designation**: Instrument Technician

Duration : 07/05/2009 to 08/12/2010

- Working in Maintenance Department doing Fault Finding and solve the fault as Requirement as per Operation Department.
- I am doing Preventive, corrective and diagnostic maintenance of all kinds of Instruments. Troubleshooting, repairing, calibration of various types of process control instruments.
- Test and maintains test equipment's, keeping records of the jobs, equipment history and calibration data's.

**Employer**: **BILAG INDUSTRIES PVT.LTD. AT VAPI** 

**Designation: Instrument Technician** 

Duration : 05/10/2006 to 30/09/2008

 Preventive, corrective and diagnostic maintenance of all kinds of Instruments. Troubleshooting, repairing, calibration of various types of process control instruments. Loop checking, precommissioning checks, up-gradation and maintenance services.

- Configuration, Calibration and maintenance of Level troll and Radar type level transmitter.
- Worked on field Instruments are mostly Smart Transmitters, Fisher, Rosemount, Level trolls, Masoneilan, Fisher make Control Valves and ROTORK MOV Actuators etc.

## A LIST OF SYSTEM/INSTRUMENTS/ EQUIPMENT HANDLED

- YOKOGAWA (Centum VP) honeywell, GE MARK VIE, BENTLY NEVADA (3500 Series)
- GAS TURBINE (GE-FRAME 9E & PGT25+), AIR COMPRESSOR (HANWA TECHNIP)
- HYDRULIC SAFETY SHUTDOWN SYSTEM (HSSS),
- ALSO WORKING IN HYDRULIC PRESSURE OPERATED VALVE (ESDV, SSSV,SSV,SLV, WV..)
- Hssd system, FACP (Fire & Gas system)
- Inergen system, co2 system

- Smart, Electronic Transmitters- Rosemount, Honeywell, and Yokogawa.
- Leveltrol- Masoneilan, Magnetrol.
- Control Valves- Masoneilan, Fisher and Valtek.
- Valves (MOV, ESDV & On/Off) Rotork and Biffi
- **Switches** Flow, Pressure, Level & Temperature
- HART-275,375 and 475, Emerson.
- Druck Calibrator-605,610,620.
- Smoke Detectors -FANWAL, SIEMENS, CERBERUS
- Flame Detectors -Detronics, honeywell, genaral monitor,
- Heat Detectors –honeywell, general monitors
- Gas Detectors (toxic, mithan) Detronics, General Monitor, honeywell.
- Manual Call Point Thorn Security, MEDC.

#### **PERSONAL DATA**

Name : Patel Dipeshbhai Ramubhai

Date of Birth : 29-11-1987

Nationality : Indian

Gender : Male

Family Status : UN married

Passport No. : k5600637

Issue Date : 11/10/2012

Expire Date : 10/10/2022

Address : At&Po: Bodali, Tal: Jalalpore

Dist.: Navsari, Pin: 396445,

Gujarat, India

Languages Known : English, Hindi, and Gujarati.

I hereby declare that all information given above is correct to the best of my knowledge. I further declare that if I shall be selected, I will try my level best to increase the reputation to your organization.

With favorable hopes,

Dipesh R. Patel

PLACE & DATE : \_\_\_\_\_